Everyone welcome to build twenty fifteen to the app monetize a
shun ad promotion sorry ad monetize a shun app promotion session
we're very excited to beard build this is the third day of the conference I hope you had a great
time we're here to talk about all the great things were bringing with windows ten for you to
make more money with ads and to acquire more users with app promotion my name is near frame of
...and I am program manager in the stored dead-center team and with me I have
...all oven from the advertising team and vj raj
...from the advertising team as well to talk about features that we've done so let's
go ahead and start with we're talking about why advertising matters
when you take a look at the amount of money that we pay you developers
and the windows ecosystem and this is a metric that you've seen in the analytics session that we've had and that
center session that we had yesterday a third of that money
comes from advertising so that's a hefty chunk so regardless of if
you're using add monetize a shun as your primary source of my making or if
you're leveraging other options like ip or giving a price for your app this
session is very important for you because we've done some great work and great improvements
in microsoft advertising to increase your monetize a shun let's take a look at how
microsoft advertising has been faring and I'm going to use data from the past six months to show you
year over year revenue for microsoft advertising now the important
thing to notices the orange bars are almost twice as big as a great
Yes,
we have one month that is not quite twice but still hire and this is indicative of the
momentum because you asked us to make more money with microsoft advertising and in fact
you are we're very excited about this momentum is indicative of the high...rates
and the high cp m that we can provide here at microsoft and we're hoping to continue this momentum
and twenty fifteen and beyond.
So, let's...a quick overview of the agenda for
this session first we're going to talk about app promotion successful developers
acquire users without promotion either cross-promotions which we refer to
as house ads those are ads that show up within your own apps or
page promotions those are ads for your app that show up
and other apps in the ecosystem so vj is going to talk about the great work that
has team is done in the app promotion space then we're going to move on
to the windows ten advertising sdk
...energy see twenty fifteen this year and february and I focused on the monetize
...track and analysis after analysis after analysis was showing that
even though game developers are making ninety percent of all the revenue from ip
adding advertising side-by-side with ip doesn't impact your
buyers and gives you more money so video interstitial is one of
a very specific intuitive and lucrative way of making more
ad money in your game and we've announcer a few times in the past couple days
...announcing it again video interstitial is coming to microsoft advertising and
...is going to talk about that an additional work that we've done in the sdk space for windows
stand and then finally ad mediation so back in november we released windows
at mediation for windows phone only some of you may have used it and what we call
the legacy portal and windows phone so that's
another thing that we notice successful developers do the fact is that no matter how good an
...provider is they cannot guarantee hundred-percent celebrate so if you want to maximize your
fill rate and have the ability to favor your high cp
and providers ad mediation is the solution for you and we've done some great work with windows
ad mediation to make aggregation available for all of
you so with that let's go ahead and start with promote your app so here
...build last year we announce to promote your app feature in the pub
center portal and in the past year we've got some feedback from you that we address them
...happy to make some announcements regarding that today so first of
...you wanted to have better targeting for your ad campaigns...very excited to nouns that
auto targeting an additional targeting capabilities are coming to this feature...going to talk about
dialogue that later next commonsense ical you want to be able to
calculate your costner install your cp I you can only do that if we provide install
tracking reporting we have an until now and we're very excited to say that install tracking is coming
tap promotion and then finally do you really have to get
...pub center to create an app promotion campaign for an app that you've submitted
...not anymore we're doing a lot of
work to unifier experiences such that dead-center is your one-stop-shop and
now app promotion lives there even today with preview and it's the best q with my
pleasure to invite vj to talk about the great work that they've done app promotion?
Fantastic...air it's great to be back had
built hope you're having a fantastic time.
I'm going to talk about
our promotion since the launch of app promotion last year we
...added number of capabilities to help you get new users
to acquisition particularly I want to highlight the range of capabilities we've
added starting from better design capabilities to
intuitive visibly tools for you to construct your ad design custom tag links new
markets support and more importantly support for promoting windows ten apps as
This exposure product is already available and
used by many users and they're getting really good install tracking as well.
Today I'm happy to unknowns bunch of new capabilities that's going to further your user
acquisition
...first says knee-high later and promotion and monetize
...or deeply integrated in-depth center what it means is as soon as
you publisher...and your app goes live you can promote your...right within in-depth center.
By default we have enabled you for auto targeting at no extra cost.
...understand the user base of your app we understand the install base of your app so
be auto target your campaigns easily to drive more installs
for-you however if you decide to use manual targeting to
target specific demographically geography age or gender you could do so using
or manual targeting capability.
Then we've been working very hard to give you install tracking metrics.
Due to the proliferation of legacy ad...case we're launching
...install tracking capability as beta during the beta period we're going to work with
many external third-party app developers as well as third-party measurement companies to
...install tracking to make sure we give you an accurate number so
please we encourage you to take a look at it and try it out and give your feedback as we improvise
this capability I don't want to highlight that it's easy to jump on
...promotion and promote your app without putting
your credit card if you have more than one app in the store you can cross promote your
app easily in your other app slots using the cost promotion or the house
...capability so I encourage you to try it out
without using your credit card today to promote your other apps in the ads...network we are working super
...working closely with the windows team to enable many capabilities during the windows
ten journey specifically we are going to
advancing targeting capabilities during the summertime including support
for behavioral targeting as well...category...targeting as well.
Currently this exposure product is one
...available english-speaking markets we're going to make sure this
...promotion capability becomes available and other top windows markets as well so that you
can easily promote your app in other new markets as well we're working with the windows
ten many of you who attended earlier session this morning you might have understood the
campaign attribution tracking capability to attribute your install tracking so we're going to
work closely with the windows team to enable camping attribution tracking as well.
Finally as I said earlier we're working with multiple third-party companies to enable
third-party measurement for install tracking vn descended as app developer
...already promoting on writing apps and other platforms and you're used
...measurements from other third-party measurement companies as well so
we're working with a couple of companies...shared more details during the summertime free.
We've been listening to your feedbackfor a long-time all of
your key feedback in app promotion was hey this barrier for entry forming
is putting my credit card and we've also looked at our logs and lot of times people
all come all the way to saving the campaign and...see thecredit card
option they dropout so, I'm super happy to announce that we're going to support publisher
earnings what it means is if you're already having an ad enabled application
and you're making money you can set aside some portions of your earnings towards
your marketing budget is a cool feature that we're excited to land later part of this
year finally over the course of this app promotion journey since last year been working with many
big game studios as well as you share some really good success stories later.
Vone this two-d lifecycle of app marketing really well the
one of the scenario that many app development companies are doing is they have pretty good
marketing budget when they want to launch and you appso,
there's sort of a bursts experience they wanted to pop and do
a major pr when a new app is launch so
the required additional budget requirements as well to run a camping so we are increasing the
camping budget from five hundred dollars to ten thousand-dollars pretty so,
all these capabilities...assume that will be released throughout the windows
turned release timeframe during the summer and later in summer as well so to summarize you
can promote your windows pc tablet
and mobile apps easily increase these steps first thing you need
to do is essentially to construct your pop I popping design of your
ad we're giving you bunch of intuitive tools that you can use to construct your
ad design so we've also enable custom tag...so that you can get the attention of the
consumers then set targeting for your app
campaign whether you leverage the order targeting capability that you're automatically
opted into or using the manual targeting said the right targeting so-you can reach the
audience that you care about and acquired the new users finally you can measure
...effectiveness through the new analytics that we have...enable and you can understand the
various metrics such as a click to rate of your ad how many impressions
...and finally the installs as web based on the...
weaker campaigner gesture than rerun it as well let me show you how easy-to-use?
All right so.
As we highlighted I am right now in the new
...portal as you can see.
Up monetize a shun using ads and promoting...deeply integrated
in-depth center so you can immediately promote your app as soon as...app goes like.
As you can see here as part of the app ad campaign I have a bunch of camping's
already running these are the paid camping's I have positive you campaigns the camping's that are
...or inactive will show up...the inactive section and you can also
cross promote any of your apps...other apps as well and all of them will show up
...the house campaign section we have a pretty good filtering capability if you are looking for
...you know, if you want to search you can search this
...refresh...mission might of time...let me quickly go ahead and...
Well, it's loading let me go ahead and search this.
So, you have a search capability so as you run many campaigns you can easily search all the campaigns
write within the within the...that's go ahead and create a new camping
again this ad that I'm writing is essentially a movie gossip app and it's a
brand-new app I don't have any users so I need tomake a I
popping advertisement and promote this ad in the absent...network so let's give a friendly
...name this is a launch...summer launch camping.
This is again a paid campaign as I said earlier you can also run a free house camping
without putting a credit card and a enable the free house campaign you can notice that the credit
card section completely disappear so I strongly...you to
...the...if you have more than one app within the vin windows
...that's go ahead and create a paid camping since this some movie app is
targeted towards users in india so I'm going to select this country targeting as india this
...want to constructing the ad design.
As you see heavy provide a few tools for you to construct your at
...these creative elements come from what
...submitted to the windows dead-center so for instance a logo
of your app is here you can said the background design of your at creative this
is how this ad will show up in other apps since is app is free you can
selected three this app is brand-new I don't have any rating I don't want this to be a
turnoff for users to download so I'm going to remove the app rating from
a ad creative I'm going to provide a some cool custom
...length so let's call this.
Best movie app as you notice here we've also enable editorial...so that
...app meets the editorial body network so for instance if I put cool movie
sexy app it'll automatically figure out that I am
I'm violating the editorial policies so this is not allowed in this so you can be
...that one legal valid editorial...content will be allowed here.
All right so this let's libby...play around with the design this looks decent for me.
Let's let me move on to the targeting section desired design looks good again,
I'm going to opting to this auto targeting because microsoft really understands the user base
of your app so this is order targeted for-you however if I decide to use a
manual targeting I can target specific gender age and also have already
targeted country here in this particular case.
...go ahead and set of monthly budget let's say four hundred-dollars.
Since I've already used a few credit cards within microsoft services for
such as you or commerce and other places my credit cards automatically show up
here so here I've used to credit cards I can pick one of them for this campaign
how if you decide to use a new credit card you can add so right here.
Let's go ahead and review what we have done here so it's a new launch of my new
app summer campaign it's a paid...set aside hundred ten dollars for this campaign
monthly budget this is how does that is going to look it's a it's a simple banner
...go ahead and conform so one...saving...it's going to take a couple of seconds to see this
campaigns what it does is under the covers it's calling a delivery system passing all these
targeting date data and within a few seconds your camping will be ready to start serving
and other app install ax so I will while it's saving it I'm going to go back to the
install tracking report you can get to this today from the
...from the dead-center portal using this analytics section.
You see these app install...how you get to the section of the install
tracking this is a first part install tracking so as you notice here you can measure your
...using various metrics for instance how many impressions how many
if your brand goal if your goal is primarily to create
I pop and exposure of your app then you look at the number of impressions that
your...so far how many times users of
senior app you can look at the correlation between the number of impression served in the click to rate
of that the effectiveness of cdr is a important number to measure the
...effectiveness finally you can track how many installs it
led to this is essentially the first party tracking you can obviously select as many as for
campaigns here I have many campaigns running so I want
to selected one campaign to demonstrate this so you can run-up to for campaigns and
...of the effectiveness and compare them with other campaigns and,
go back and tweak your campaign the such as targeting a different country
...leveraging daughter targeting as well or even changing your
ad design sometimes that also is very critical so go ahead and say look at this is a
summer launch campaign it's still under processing and a you know,
refresh this it should come back to
...completion state what it means it's ready for serving right now so in
...next few minutes this campaign is ready to start serving your promotion will be active.
All right it's should load in a second that's wait a minute.
All right all right so this campaign is already active I can
...campaign whenever you decide if it's not working out based on the
...install tracking effectiveness you can go ahead and
posses campaign it'll go back to the inactive section so I hope it gives you
a tour of how to promote your app
...within their center in three easy steps construct your ad design set
auto targeting and measure analyze and track your install.
All right so we've been working with quite a bit of partners doing...early adoption
...preview face I do want to highlight really good impressive campaign...was run by one of
...partner is random...here I wanted to give them a
background of a plus they being a great...photos during this joining the
...recently to launch one of the...one of the noodp app that resulted
in fantastic results for them so again we are in this journey we look forward to your
feedback we will be enabling many features during the summertime in the windows ten
timeframe so with that I'm going to turn it over to near he's going to talk about
...thanks is a great work on apple
motion you should be able to try...now...around of laws proper motion.
Thank you guys.
So, I promotion is fully available
...center preview you can access to preview create campaigns consume performance reporting so
encourage you to do that so with that let's move and talk about windows ten advertising
sdk so again touching on things that you've told us in the past twelve months that you
want...the first thing we colleague have
...form my game need...any native out really needs...fast and managed
...is the...are not necessarily the best solution for out monetize a
shun I'm very excited to announce that are windows ten advertising sdk will
support native apps and that's going to talk about that shortly next every time we
released...those of you...been using the microsoft advertising as again the past every time we released
and you version if you wanted to enjoy the goodness that comes without version
you needed to integrated into your app which resulted in an app update app updates are costly
for-you their painful for users so again very excited to announce that the windows ten
...sdk will be shipped as an os framework which means that we can...goodness without you
need to make any go changes and you just get it for free when the store updates so that's
another good thing and then finally you asked for more ad experiences and we've
announce it several times and I'm going to do it yet again video interstitial
as which is a big deal is coming to microsoft advertising and I'm very excited to invite
...to the stage to talk about the windows sent ad sdk and also
why video interstitial is something that you want to start working with right now thanks-a-lot near.
I'm happy to announce for the fourth time that we have video interstitial ads
and there's really three reasons why you would want to use video interstitial ads
number-one the money right number two
it's a better fit for a lot of games a number three is super easy to do so I want to touch
on each of those three points in terms of money is actually a product that
the yields accordingly marketer ten-x what the banner ads
too now before you start getting all the greedy
so to speak you have to bear in mind that banner ads
you rotating every sixty seconds and you're not going to do that probably
with video ads but you still will have a higher overall revenue
you can you can count on that the second thing it touch on is
...is a better fit especially for games right you guys have all
seen this before we have we have a game which kind of share both the
...in the game play on the same screen user accidently clicks the add
...a cuts a constant problem so for user experience reasons as well as
performance if your direct decks game you're trying to show html on the scene screen the same time
as direct acts as a much better thing to be able to sort of swap out the screens.
So, for both user experience and for performance reasons it's a good fit and lastly it's
easy to integrate and how easy to integrate I hear you cry so,
easy a program manager can do it so let
me with that show you my game so I'm going
to go switch gears here and head right into visual studio?
Okay.
So, the first thing that I wanted to point
out maybe even use the pointer thank you.
The first thing that I wanted to point out is that there's no longer such thing up and there
is a any cpu since we're native library you are going to have to switch to
architecture specific outputs so in this case I'm using x eighty-six
is my output the second thing that I wanted to point out of highlighted
already is that it is the very same name space as the banner ads if
you're using the banner ads so that also means is coming from the same sdk so
you don't have to go download something different it's...be...the same sdk.
And, I'll show you what the heart and soul.
...api...which is really for events actually I kind of glossed over you have to obviously
instantiate control...it but...therefore events in those for of
answers follows the ad ready event is fired ...the point in time
at between requesting...and you're going to show it so unlike banner as we
...to have a synchronous go fetch and show it all-in-one transaction through the refresh
call with video interstitial...you want to prefix those ads and you're doing that because you don't want
to leave the user hanging while we're gone and fetching a video which is a much
...substantially larger asset than...banner ads.
So, the next two things that you see up I have something on top sorry
cancelled and completed those two can fire off during the playback of the
ads of the user decides to bail-out of the...early you get a
...event if the user goes and watches the adult way through the
n which is what we want you'll get the completed events and why do we want the user watch the
whole thing well we're going to get a lot better revenue if we have
high completion right so we encourage that and lastly there's the error occurred event the error
...event is exactly the same as...banner ads and just so,
you know, very rarely would you ever see those come during ad playback
...most frequently going to happen during the ad fetch?
So, without in like it's kind of glossed over another colleges request ads you quest
add-in show at those the final two things I happen to wrap them into my own method because I'm calling various
ad units to for the sake of this demo but, you would otherwise just call
...ad dot requests...very simple.
So, with that let me go ahead and run my program manager game.
It is the best game ever I hope you enjoy it okay it's a throwback.
So, let me say this is maybe the first and only time you're going to
see microsoft guy up on a stage happy to see a blue screen so thank you very much.
And, the second thing that I wanted to point out the reason I
picked it old-school primitive game-like this is...two reasons one it's easy to program
honestly but secondly it also has to show that really doesn't matter what that games genre is we could put
video ads and anything so without further ado I'm going-to go ahead and accept
the value proposition that's been offered to me here the to start level two I'm going to
watcher video okay that's cool I got a for free tomorrow with this.
The as you're okay.
There for two reasons.
One it makes my game looked that much more primitive the to of
...a thousand times but anyway it's a gorgeous that so
you see what happens now is that I've said.
You gotta watch the whole thing so obviously I wired up that
...event that I showed you before to basically encourage user you going to go watch the
whole thing so all right and game again I got...for free some happy I watch
the whole thing spoiler alert this is actually a home video and I enlisting the help of my
family to show this...
What staff why some of the advertising disclosure that tells and
app is advertisement not regular content?
The number that's the countdown on the
...time tells you how much time's left in the admass me.
Was a little more than three this happens to be a very long at the most at the...fifteen
...seconds reasons...very expensive to make video as
...a...backbone because I haven't clinton's
...yet pshaw moi.
...going to learn more about okay, wait...can't...at...
umass euclid...more moi.
...button will appear in...that actually have
...in this case you'll notice that we now
...slit...in windows phone...actually get
...rather but you're always just one back but...
Cheap laborI did give a cookie for the record okay moi.
All right so I know you're thinking gee map that's nice you can put a fake at in the
fake game how about a real...real game and I know they got a
...before I'm not even sure if the here is...random sell guys here?
I guess not ok well random salad was the first to put
our video interstitial out liveso, I have little video clip to show you
...again, that they created running on a...in live today.
And, I kept silent so I could
...on top of the video and what you'll notice that they did is that they basically did
appear interstitial so the very end of this level I'm not particularly great at this game you'll
see that automatically we come up with an ad...interrupt the user was all done plane that level
of comes the add this at doesn't have a learn more link because it doesn't have a clicked web action they don't
...have that but otherwise looks the same as the windows one and you can activate
the back button exactly same thing so that is our first app out in the...using video
...through a close pilot congratulations...random valid?
next step is what is going to go over some of the best practices I alluded to some of them when I was
shown you the demo but this is more or less a laundry list of
come to affectionately show note a should know these next slide is the nags
...which is kind of do this don't do that.
So, if you bear with me so the best practices is it really got
to think about these ads during the design...don't think you're going to just design the game and kinda come in the and
slap in slap in the ads you can get away with that with the banner ads with interstitial ads with the
prevention all of those events that your wiring really figure out where in the workflow
...sense and you...really show it right roger...is doing a demo in the theater
later today at two thirty I believe you can go see a real like direct
x game and he's written cplus-plus it's really cool demos were seen so,
natural breaks it's kind of self-explanatory...my brakes were if it's
Sports title he might have a between innings
...your game you'll know where to put those ads.
Associate with tangible...is basically
...the user is getting value out of the ads so, for example,
you might have a hint if it's a puzzle game is a puzzle game you may...I can go
...the game or might be an extra life or might be more time to finish
...level those are those are examples of good tangible...to give the user and
...you want to continually improve don't think that you're just going to like
releases in let it go you really want to look at our reports and make sure that your
ads are performing well and, you know,...
remake changes you need to in re submit then let's...the worst practices so
...you guys have probably seen some of these so some examples so showing ads
apps start it seems like that would be a great placement because well I'm going to get a lot of
money from it seemingly...a short-term strategy because the first few users who just click a
...going to be confuse they're going to think they launched the media app or something and they are
paragon rate your app pretty poorly so I would avoid that interrupting users imagine I'm
clicking all those bubbles and lo and behold something that
comes up out of nowhere that's not a very good placement don't do that.
Back-to-back ad so just imagine I was getting ready to play level to
...excited I'm watching the...go down it's zero lo and behold it pops up another added
...fifteen or thirty seconds that's you can do at the api...will allow
it but that's definitely going to have some user backlash you...avoid
and leslie's rewarding with exchangeable currency so if you're actually giving out real money or even anything that's
that can be traded with other users in your app ecosystem do you want to
avoid that because you really opening ourselves up to hackers and hackers tend to win.
And, you have to keep up with them right.
These are just the sample so when you go in and get our bits and get the documentation make sure
you read all the best practices I was just giving you sort...sampling for the sake of time.
want to sum it up what you just saw a few other goodies so.
The best practices can be summed up in a single sentence make a good game the money's going
to follow trust me and then secondly let's talk about the availability
of already told you...and pilot today it's in a close pilot we're out there eight-hour one
...both phone and on windows and windows ten you can go download the
bit's now and they work with the very same visual studio twenty fifteen and,
the os is was just ship for this conference in fact that's what I'm running now and will be
release ready in association with the windows ten launch timeframe?
Other benefits near already talked about it...recap it were native that means we don't...the
net framework...is a framework that means we don't have to be distributed the library if we
have a forbid have a bug in we need to patch that you don't need to go and...admit that package
...depend only...universal windows platforms...with this whole conferences about is the new you know,
the new single run-time that runs across all devices that's all we depend upon so that's all
you're apathy...depends upon take on the...sdk.
And, finally the consist we consolidate installer
...with the mediation so the work that nears team is doing is going to be all right
...one installer so one-stop-shop no matter which platform
you targeting in the past and we had our ads and app site we had a whole bunch of rows and you had to figure
out example and...phone that now there's going to a single endpoint very easy to find and installer
...the case so universal we are the universal ad client teams so what is universal mean to me
I mean several things that means universal by device any windows
ten device we have you covered so...the tablet of phone a desktop it doesn't matter
we support universal terms of programming languages so we support javascript we
support csharp we support the visual basic anyone...to using
...okay with it doesn't matter with support any programming language and we'll support in the app model
already talked about and showed use animal we also support html?
And, we also support direct decks through the sample direct interop.
And, by the way this last year probably one of the things I've felt most bad about
...that we didn't deliver on time to have ww a or
...the html apps covered on the ate out one stack with it and we do now
if you are in that in that category come see...be able...the beta.
And, with that I'm going to turn it back to near.
Thank you very much.
Cute kid.
Let's see if I could follow that up with some windows
at mediation free to get excited about so we talked about
our promotions we talked about the new sdk let's talk about
ad mediation.
As I said before ad mediation is something that successful developers do in order to maximize their
fill rates and...their high
...and providers however mediation is very complicated and costly
you need to find the right assemblies you need to read multiple documentations you need to implement
multiple codes for different providers and that's before even start with your mediation configuration and even then
one mediation configuration is likely not going to work free very well if you're app is successful
...more than one market because different ad providers are performing differently
in different geography's so like I said back in november of
twenty fourteen were released windows ad mediation for phone and we're very excited to say that as soon as
...center exits preview and you can start submitting apps
in-depth center you will be able to take advantage of windows
...mediation for all your apps and it addresses all these
...points another one that I wanted to call out separately is that if you do implement
your own mediation every time you make changes that mediation configuration and you
will have to make multiple changes to that because it's a dynamic configuration between different
providers...it results in a code change that requires you to build your app and send
...update which as we said before is costly for you and it's painful for users
if you set up jan service to do that it is also extremely expensive and windows...mediation does that
for-you you-can go-to deb center and you can create configurations
...specific markets and change them as many times
as you want and they will be consumed by applications that without
needed without the need of an app update and then finally we touched on that before is do I really
need to go to...center in order to monetize with adds the app that I've submitted
...dead-center well the answer is no again very excited to have created
red carpet white glove more expletives for?
To make it easy for you to use microsoft advertising for your
ad monetize a shun and with
that let's go ahead and jump to a demo to show you exactly how that looks.
All right so I went ahead and created this windows application in visual studio twenty
fifteen and the first thing that I'm going to do is you'll know that here the tool-box I have an
ad mediator control that would be the new ad control so I'm going-to go ahead I'm going to drag
at controls to the designer to the...I want to show ads
so I'm going to put one at the top left and one of the bottom right now I'm going to give
them meaningful names the reason I'm going to do that is when I upload this package
...center I will need to configure the metadata for the participating ad networks so it helps that
the control is identifiable for-you in-depth center some going to call this one top
And, I'm going to call this one bottom...
Now I talked about red carpets and white gloves whether I mean for those of you
of monetize without center in the past, you know, that you needed to create account...center
...payout api create attacks profile generate app ideas and add unit
...copy pace them into your code that you've implemented specifically for microsoft advertising before
you could build and upload...center by dragging the control from the toolbox
...the designer we've implemented everything for you if you want to monetize
...microsoft advertising your done once you've drive those controls you can build your app and
you can submit to dead-center however before we do that we also
mention that successful developers use ad mediation in order to maximize fill rates and favor high
cp and providers so I highly recommend you take advantage of the
ad mediation feature that is built into this at control in order
to do that from the project menu you can go ahead and add and you connected service.
And, you'll know that ad mediator is one of those connect services available for-you
so the first thing you'll see is...microsoft advertising by default is already part of our
project and we knew that let's go ahead and select additional ad networks I'm going to choose...duplex
...in this case.
Now is like okay.
Tvs goes to know get to grab the right assemblies for this project type from ad duplex
since model we've worked with those companies to go ahead and get their assemblies
tuner get and for us to make the decision on which assemblies to grabs so
you no longer need to find those you no longer need to deal with
adding the references once I had okay I can see the
three participating and networks now before we exit connected services I do want to call
out the configure option that is available for each one of the providers so let's highlight
...duplex and hit configure this is an optional step where you can enter the metadata the
you've retrieved from the ad duplex portal the reason you would use it here is if you want to
silo your app or if you want to ts
...local machine in the case of a windows app and you want to test that metadata you
retrieve chose live ads you would use it here this is an optional step so
I'm not going to do that and we're just going-to go ahead and add and of course the background
goes away which is easily fixable by loading main page again.
And, we're ready to go all we need to do now is build our app and uploaded into
...now before we moved to dead-center
in see the experience there I do want to call out that we've implemented a bunch of events on these
...controls that you can register to encode and either
...consul or to your own logs for testing purposes we have extensive
documentation on all the event registration and practices that we recommend you
...visual studio so let's go ahead and move to dead-center now
I already created ...app and the preview that center called ...twenty fifteen for the
one and I've created a submission and
for demo purposes I already went ahead and uploaded and identical package to the one which is
created visual studio the first thing that you'll node is that there's a configure
ad mediation link in the details section for that package
that's go ahead and click that it's going to take us to the
...page for that app which is also available from the left
...menu under the monetize a shun parent in the context of that
up so let's take a look at the...well the first thing that we're going to do is we're going to choose the package that
...configuring since there are multiple...providers
...that work from multiple app types we're going to configure on a
package by package basis so let's go ahead and continue
configuring the package you that we just uploaded
right next is the target baseline here is to distinguish from a
market specific configuration if you don't create a market specific
configuration baseline is going to be used everywhere and I'm going to show you a little bit later how to create a
market specific configuration where it makes sense then you can enter your global refresh rate that's
going to work across all the participating providers and now where
the mediation configuration new so let's go ahead and take a look at that so the first thing that you will
note is that microsoft advertising is by default getting a hundred-percent of the distribution
and also that we added a logical provider for microsoft advertising
house ads that is at by default...to backup vj talked about
...promotions and cross-promotions with has campaigns if you create has campaigns
you can then configure them and mediate them with other ad providers that are
participating in your package so we're going to get to that shortly next...also notice that ad
duplex since model are both set to an active by default.
Now the reason for that is there's
actually required metadata for both these providers that you need to enter
...center before we can start showing
...those providers that's metadata that you've retrieved from their portals so in this case I
went ahead and entered it I will call out the one we talked about connected services
and visual studio if you remember that optional feature to configure your providers
for testing purposes if you took advantage of that we are going to...populated
for-you in-depth center so that you don't have to do it again however dead-center is the source of
truth and we would still require that you review this metadata and hidden explicit save so
...go ahead and collapse these two since we have the metadata
...configure them so I'm going to choose ad duplex to be a backup provider and I'm going-to go
ahead and give smart to thirty percent of the distribution now you
will know the microsoft advertising by default decreases seventy percent because the some
of the distribution must always equal hundred now let's explain what
it means that microsoft is at seventy percent...model is...thirty every time the
...control is ready to request...we roll the dice we call that
a mediation session now seventy percent of the time in this case we're going to request ad
from microsoft advertising and thirty percent of the time we're going to request
...from smarter if one doesn't have an
...we're going to try the other if both don't have an added we're going to try one of our
backup providers so let's go ahead and save this baseline configuration and
wallets saving and by the way I will just point out
...any metadata for microsoft advertising it's all done for
...writing so while this well this finish saving let's talk about a
market specific scenario so let's assume that I.
...the game in the argentinean market just for my argentinean customers and
that I have multiple apps and games and the argentinean market so let's go ahead and create
and argentina's specific configuration so from the target I'm going-to go ahead I'm going
to choose argentina and then you will note that first inherits from the baseline so that
you're starting point.
Now I've created house campaign for this new game in argentina and I would actually like to
make an investment and use ten percent of my supply to show this cross
promotional campaign so I'm going-to go ahead I'm going to change house ads going-to-take it all the way
to ten percent and I'm going-to go ahead and lock it so that I can configure the other providers without
impacting that number now let's assume that's model is faring horribly...argentina and we never
want to call-in argentina not even as a backup we can go ahead and we can...all the way
to an active the assemblies for smart or still going to be part of the package that is
in the catalog...devices and argentine are never going to call smart...not even as a
backup now let's assume the opposite let's assume that's motto is exceptionally well
in argentina and in fact we wanted to be the dominant provider there we can go ahead and move
smarter let's move it all the way to eighty percent.
Microsoft advertising reduced to ten percent we keep our ten percent investment in our house
campaign this looks good let's go ahead and say this market specific configuration so
the last piece is how devices and argentine actually
going to start behaving according to this mediation so we set up a service
that allows all the devices out there in the world to call home every twenty four hours and
...you configuration is available so in this case since we just created the
...configuration all the devices running my app and argentina are going to
start consuming this configuration and acting by it.
So, to finish off the windows
ad mediation section let's go and take a look at reporting so since I
wanted to use and...that actually has a lot of traffic and...of users and has been using successfully the
...mediator we chose an internal successful developers app called
...hd and let's take a look at the
aggregation reports that are available under the analytics heading and the context of your...and I'm going
to go over those fairly quickly their well-documented and we can continue talking about them also after the
session so the first report is just your general ad mediation performance
...it shows your ...rate the
number of mediation sessions and then the number of ads delivered let's go back to the
fill rate you'll know that in this case the average...rate is a hundred-percent I do want to call out
the charts here use as an...value the
mean value for the data available and in fact the mean value here is ninety nine-point-five
for so this developers achieving
and near one hundred percent failure rate in fact mathematically rounded to hundred-percent
...rate using windows at mediation now this developers using all these
at providers five ad providers and we provide you also with the
fill rate for each one of those and this is a straightforward
...rate calculation which is basically ads delivered divided by requests?
Finally there's a unique users per mediation configuration so if you
recall we created a specific configuration for argentina but let's take a more
a simpler example the other configuration you've looked at the cp m across all
your providers and now you want to make a change to favor a provider that now is the high
...provider you go to the configuration you make the changes
...you want to know at which point you have a critical mass of devices
and users who have consume this configuration before you make decisions whether to
keep that configuration or to make edits to it and in this charge you'll be able to see
and this example we see that there's there's a very dominance configuration that applies
...the majority of users and then finally we provide you
to error breakdowns the first one just gives you the error rate for each
...provider and it's a it's a straightforward what percent percentage of all
ad requests resulted in an error instead of a valid response now I want to point out that
a valid response would be either an ads or no
...right not having demand is not an error case but then let's say that,
for example, here and interactively see sixteen percent error rate if you want to know
what's causing those errors we provide an additional error breakdown by type and this is a new
report that we have that we that doesn't exist in the windows phone portal right now so
...the case of interactive we can see that there's two error types that are contributing to all
their errors and eighty three percent of all the eras are related to this one so
in our documentation we provide explanation on each one of those
...types and the right strategies to address them and reduce them.
So, with that let's go back to the presentation.
So, currently side-by-side with microsoft we have seven mediation partners that are already
practicing participating with windows at mediation and more coming in the pipeline if
you using it for windows phone you'll be able to consume your reports in the
previewed of center however you will not be able to make configuration changes to
configurations done in the windows phone portal bear with us for a few more weeks and once the
preview dead-center opens up you'll be open for business with windows at mediation and we're very excited to
see how you like it all right so let's summarize what we talked about today and we started out
we're talking about app promotion and we talked about how we added...targeting
and additional manual targeting capabilities and also we're going to start reporting on
installs so you can calculates dpi then we moved on to talk about the windows ten
ad sdk how it supports native apps how it's going to be shipped...an
...framework so that you don't have to update your app whenever we update
our sdk and how interstitial ads for the fifth...
...announce now for microsoft advertising it is actually a big deal you have an opportunity to make a
lot more money in your apps and games and then finally we talked about
ad mediation and how windows
...mediation makes it very easy for you to plug-and-play third-party
ad providers?
Getting a high...rate and favoring your icy
...providers and then finally...like the one meta
...point is no more will you have to go to multiple portals dead-center is truly
your one-stop-shop for app development and add monetize a shun
an app promotion so we're very excited about that and hopefully so are you.
All right so little bit of call-to-action will first of all like I said promoter app is available
and preview dead-center so go and use it and until
preview dead-center becomes the only
dead-center available pub center is going to continue being alive so
go ahead and start comparing create campaigns and pub...see them show up in the preview
...compare the reports do it in the other direction create
campaigns and the preview dead-center see them appear and pubs center and one thing that I
actually than mention and I'm not going to switch back now to dep center but at the bottom of every
...center page we have a feedback charm please,
please use that feedback charm and let us know what you like
what you don't like where view that feedback on a daily basis and we
...we make decisions on design changes and you exchanges based on what
we hear from you hide the nets call-to-action is download
...integrate the preview for the windows ten atis
...in the learn more
link here and microsoft advertising build blog you will find instructions on how to
do that so start playing with interstitial ads start playing with
native implementation for your absolution from microsoft advertising
second and this is something that or third rather something that mapped mentioned at two
thirty in about an hour and ten minutes you're going to
have the last chance to see the theater demo at the demo theater.
How roger?
They are right next to quick start is on second-floor,
second-floor, second-floor I think it's right across from the restroom...that.
So, direct the video ads come seethe last chance to see
that demo and then something that I already mentioned give us feedback give us feedback
in person give us feedback in email give us feedback in the feedback charm
in-depth center and we're going to be in the insider lounge for comic the next
...to ninety minutes so any of you here in the whole want to have a conversation
can definitely come over and ask and we're happy to help
and I think that we have about seven minutes left for q and a right here?
So, actually before we as you line-up for q and
a I do...to point out that we want to make build a better conference for
you and the only way we can do that is if we hear from you
and each session did you get enough details do not get enough details did you like the
presenters paramount's kid...and evaluation so fleas
...the q r code entered to win a prize and let us have a better build
for your next year and without...and a if there are any questions.
...above so about how sets mr going to...custom designs are
only predefined or used there are also going to be an interstitial
...duets of in a great question so.
...house a
...that we support is very limited today we're going to expand more
creative solutions later whatever is available today I showed you is only creative options available to
constructive create things interstitial certainly now that we have
a enabled through the...educate we will also support
that to construct the you know, your design as well so it's not it in
...but certainly...look into it you can make some home videos moi.
Thanks for the feedback moi.
...interstitial...mediation,
mediation for interstitial so...the out of the
gate we're not going to support mediation for interstitial I do want to point out that when you...that
...control on to the designer all the references required in order to implement interstitial your
...have already taken care of we are thinking about mediation for interstitial right now the only
provider that works on the windows ecosystem is microsoft advertising and
So, let's actually talk about that...definitely thinking of mediation for interstitial but
of the gate we're not going to have mediation fairness st.
Our question about install tracking real you do integrations
with a third parties
...to send this information back to them
to like most of the install...companies the what they do the
provide special urls for.
Each partner network that and information
is post back to that network so, for example, if you like advertise with
us and use a instill...from
...they will send the information back to asked our...
result...will there be something on this was so
this so obviously currently...are not exposing that beta occur as I
mentioned earlier we're also moving into the camping attribution tracking that windows
ten provides I would done right so with the first party campaign attribution that
...releasing with windows ten we're making it easy for you to
...the url that will direct to the to the page you
on the store and then if there's a conversion the attribution
...that conversion is stored as part of the what we
call the entitlement what that really means for you is that when the app runs
it will have programmatic access to that attribution a lot of the way that these
third-party implementations work is that they give you a piece of sdk that app launch will
go and grab the attribution somehow and, then send it to that third-party so
they can match the click event with the conversion so we are
absolutely enabling that with the first party attribution solution from windows
tent and we are also collaborating closely with
the advertising team for them to onboard that solution the details haven't been
figured out yet but that absolutely were aware this is a top requirement for
the campaign attribution feature and were fully committed to making that feature fully baked?
Thank you.
Do you have an example ofgave more apt that could have made a lot more
...it would have used data advertisement in about...
As you so loaded...the short answer is yes however,
we are limited in what disclosure we can do
informs like that so how about you come to the insider...and we can have some more
one-on-one conversation but could you say what they did wrong without specifying
the up or something so I may have misunderstood the question did wrong
...what regard in how the use of a advertise and steps to make money.
So, I wouldn't say that there's examples of how people
used advertising offering wrong I think that there are capabilities are you
referring to the to the interstitial in particular or no...on read layout
to make mana with advertisement...so games so, you know,
I would say that this really touches on the meta point that we were making this session right if you're not using
ad mediation you are leaving money on the ground if you're not using interstitial ads in
addition to banner ads you are leaving money on the ground if you're not acquiring more users with
our app promotion cross-promotions feature you are missing out on users
that otherwise engage with your app increase your supply which will then result
and more money for you especially with that mediation so the cycle continues so I wouldn't say that
there's are wrong approach I mean you could definitely implemented in a way that
...codebook wouldn't work but I think...developers need to remember
is that we have a lot more opportunity and windows ten to increase your
dollars from advertising either through user acquisition or
through our mediation and the additional...experiences solutions ok thank you?
So, for the ad mediation what can we expect for some of the providers that I think
they mainly target mobile now with universal windows apps if we set up at
...we are they just not going to fill those or how does that
can so, you know,...I can say about this and we should continue more
...as we are working aggressively with many partners
to on board...onto the windows ecosystem support from
...app provider perspective we're also thinking about how we can architect
ad mediation in such a way that would enable multiple
ad providers to come...easily to the windows ecosystem so
we in fact I can provide any details right now but we expect
significant...in the number of mediation partners following that we architecture...
that's kinda like it's more like a strategies future
coming facing thinking but we're engaged in that thinking right now?
All right we're just on time again thank you very much and maybe cod insider
Thank you.